type Question = {
    question: string;
    answers: string[];
    correctAnswer: string;
  };


export const bonedata = {
    questions: [
    {
        question: "The architecture and proportion of compact and spongy bone vary according to function. The amount of compact bone is greatest in",
        answers: ["Long bones",
         "Short bones",
         "Flat bones",
         "Irregular bones",
         "Sesamoid bones"],
        correctAnswer: "Long bones"
    },
    {
        question: "Markings and features of bones appear wherever tendons, ligaments, and fascias are attached or where arteries lie adjacent to or enter bones. Spool-like articular process or process that acts as a pulley is called",
        answers: ["condyle",
         "Tubercle",
         "Trochlea",
         "Fossa",
         "Spine"],
        correctAnswer: "Trochlea",
    },    
    {
        question: "The axial skeleton consists of the bones of the head (cranium or skull), neck (hyoid bone and cervical vertebrae), and trunk that includes ribs, sternum, vertebrae, and",
        answers: "Humerus",
        "option2": "Hip bone",
        "option3": "sacrum",
        "option4": "Femur",
        "option5": "Clavicle",
        correctAnswer: "sacrum"
    },
    {
        "question": "The appendicular skeleton consists of the bones of the limbs, including those forming the pectoral (shoulder) and pelvic girdles. Which bone belong to Pectoral girdle?",
        answers: ["Radius",
         "Ischium",
         "Pubic bone",
         "Scapula",
         "Sacrum"],
        correctAnswer: "Scapula",
    },
    {
        "question": "The appendicular skeleton consists of the bones of the limbs, including those forming the pectoral (shoulder) and pelvic girdles. Which bone belong to Pelvic girdle?",
        answers: ["Radius",
         "Hip bone",
         "Femur",
         "Scapula",
         "Tibia"],
        correctAnswer: "Hip bone",
    },
    {
        "question": "Bone is a living tissue capable of changing its structure as the result of the stresses to which it is subjected. What primarily causes the hardness of bone?",
        answers: ["Presence of fibers",
         "Presence of calcium salts",
         "Blood supply",
         "Presence of periosteum",
         "Presence of bone marrow"],
        correctAnswer: "Presence of calcium salts"
    },
    {
        question: "What type of bone consists of a branching network of trabeculae?",
        answers: ["Compact bone",
         "Cortical bone",
         "Spongy bone",
         "Flat bone",
         "Irregular bone"],
        correctAnswer: "Spongy bone"
    },
    {
        question: "Which type of bone is found in the limbs and has a tubular shaft?",
        answers: ["Short bones",
         "Long bones",
         "Flat bones",
         "Irregular bones",
         "Sesamoid bones"],
        correctAnswer: "Long bones"
    },
    {
        question: "What is the thin connective tissue sheath covering the outer part of the shaft of long bones called?",
        answers: ["Perichondrium",
         "Endosteum",
         "Periosteum",
         "Epimysium",
         "Fascia"],
        correctAnswer: "Periosteum"
    },
    {
        "question": "Short bones are primarily found in which parts of the body?",
        answers: ["Skull",
         "Limbs",
         "Hand and foot",
         "Spine",
         "Pelvis"],
        correctAnswer: "Hand and foot"
    }
  ] as Question[]
};
    
//     ,
//     {
//         "question": "What is the main function of sesamoid bones?",
//         "option1": "Support weight",
//         "option2": "Protect organs",
//         "option3": "Reduce friction on tendons",
//         "option4": "Store minerals",
//         "option5": "Produce blood cells",
//         "ans": 3
//     },
//     {
//         "question": "Which type of bone marrow is predominantly found in adults?",
//         "option1": "Red marrow",
//         "option2": "Yellow marrow",
//         "option3": "Brown marrow",
//         "option4": "Green marrow",
//         "option5": "White marrow",
//         "ans": 2
//     },
//     {
//         "question": "What term describes the area where the diaphysis meets the epiphyseal plate in a growing bone?",
//         "option1": "Epiphysis",
//         "option2": "Diaphysis",
//         "option3": "Metaphysis",
//         "option4": "Periosteum",
//         "option5": "Endosteum",
//         "ans": 3
//     },
//     {
//         "question": "What is the term for the small nodules of bone found in certain tendons?",
//         "option1": "Irregular bones",
//         "option2": "Short bones",
//         "option3": "Sesamoid bones",
//         "option4": "Long bones",
//         "option5": "Flat bones",
//         "ans": 3
//     },
//     {
//         "question": "What is the main component of the extracellular matrix that gives bone its hardness?",
//         "option1": "Collagen fibers",
//         "option2": "Elastic fibers",
//         "option3": "Calcium salts",
//         "option4": "Proteoglycans",
//         "option5": "Water",
//         "ans": 3
//     },
//     {
//         "question": "Which bone type is characterized by a thin shell of compact bone and an interior of cancellous bone?",
//         "option1": "Long bones",
//         "option2": "Short bones",
//         "option3": "Flat bones",
//         "option4": "Irregular bones",
//         "option5": "Sesamoid bones",
//         "ans": 4
//     },
//     {
//         "question": "What process describes the direct development of bone from a connective tissue membrane?",
//         "option1": "Endochondral ossification",
//         "option2": "Membranous ossification",
//         "option3": "Intramembranous ossification",
//         "option4": "Periosteal ossification",
//         "option5": "Epiphyseal ossification",
//         "ans": 3
//     },
//     {
//         "question": "Which type of bone formation involves replacing a cartilaginous model with bone?",
//         "option1": "Membranous ossification",
//         "option2": "Endochondral ossification",
//         "option3": "Intramembranous ossification",
//         "option4": "Periosteal ossification",
//         "option5": "Epiphyseal ossification",
//         "ans": 2
//     },
//     {
//         "question": "What is the fibrous tissue layer covering all bone surfaces except the articulating surfaces called?",
//         "option1": "Perichondrium",
//         "option2": "Endosteum",
//         "option3": "Periosteum",
//         "option4": "Epimysium",
//         "option5": "Fascia",
//         "ans": 3
//     },
//     {
//         "question": "Which bones are developed rapidly by the membranous method in the embryo to protect the developing brain?",
//         "option1": "Long bones",
//         "option2": "Short bones",
//         "option3": "Flat bones",
//         "option4": "Irregular bones",
//         "option5": "Sesamoid bones",
//         "ans": 3
//     },
//     {
//         "question": "What is the name of the structure that serves as a storage area for calcium salts and houses bone marrow?",
//         "option1": "Cartilage",
//         "option2": "Periosteum",
//         "option3": "Bone",
//         "option4": "Tendon",
//         "option5": "Ligament",
//         "ans": 3
//     },
//     // {
//     //     "question": "What condition results from defective mineralization of the cartilage matrix in growing bones?",
//     //     "option1": "Osteoporosis",
//     //     "option2": "Rickets",
//     //     "option3": "Arthritis",
//     //     "option4": "Fracture",
//     //     "option5": "Osteomyelitis",
//     //     "ans": 2
//     // },
//     {
//         "question": "Different bone cells are assigned different roles. Which cells are responsible for bone resorption?",
//         "option1": "Osteoblasts",
//         "option2": "Chondrocytes",
//         "option3": "Osteocytes",
//         "option4": "Osteoclasts",
//         "option5": "Fibroblasts",
//         "ans": 4
//     },
//     {
//         "question": "What is the primary role of red bone marrow?",
//         "option1": "Store fat",
//         "option2": "Produce blood cells",
//         "option3": "Store calcium",
//         "option4": "Provide structural support",
//         "option5": "Produce collagen",
//         "ans": 2
//     },
//     {
//         "question": "Which type of bone marking describes a rounded elevation for muscle or ligament attachment?",
//         "option1": "Facet",
//         "option2": "Fossa",
//         "option3": "Tubercle",
//         "option4": "Notch",
//         "option5": "Canal",
//         "ans": 3
//     },
//     {
//         "question": "Which surface marking is an opening through a bone, usually for passage of blood vessels and nerves?",
//         "option1": "Fissure",
//         "option2": "Foramen",
//         "option3": "Meatus",
//         "option4": "Sulcus",
//         "option5": "Fossa",
//         "ans": 2
//     },
//     {
//         "question": "Which term describes the plate of cartilage between the diaphysis and epiphysis in a growing bone?",
//         "option1": "Periosteum",
//         "option2": "Endosteum",
//         "option3": "Metaphysis",
//         "option4": "Epiphyseal plate",
//         "option5": "Diaphysis",
//         "ans": 4
//     },
//     {
//         "question": "What is the primary composition of the outer part of the shaft of long bones?",
//         "option1": "Cancellous bone",
//         "option2": "Compact bone",
//         "option3": "Cartilage",
//         "option4": "Spongy bone",
//         "option5": "Fibrous tissue",
//         "ans": 2
//     },
//     {
//         "question": "Which cells are found in the deeper surface of the periosteum and have bone-forming capability?",
//         "option1": "Osteoclasts",
//         "option2": "Chondrocytes",
//         "option3": "Osteocytes",
//         "option4": "Osteoblasts",
//         "option5": "Fibroblasts",
//         "ans": 4
//     },
//     {
//         "question": "Which type of bone fracture is commonly accompanied by displacement due to muscle pull?",
//         "option1": "Fracture of the ilium",
//         "option2": "Fracture of the neck of the femur",
//         "option3": "Fracture of the clavicle",
//         "option4": "Fracture of the radius",
//         "option5": "Fracture of the ulna",
//         "ans": 2
//     },
//     {
//         "question": "What role do Sharpey's fibers play in bone structure?",
//         "option1": "Attach muscles to bone",
//         "option2": "Extend from periosteum into bone",
//         "option3": "Provide blood supply to bone",
//         "option4": "Act as bone-forming cells",
//         "option5": "Form bone marrow",
//         "ans": 2
//     },
//     {
//         "question": "Which bone type is cuboidal in shape and primarily found in the hand and foot?",
//         "option1": "Long bones",
//         "option2": "Short bones",
//         "option3": "Flat bones",
//         "option4": "Irregular bones",
//         "option5": "Sesamoid bones",
//         "ans": 2
//     },
//     {
//         "question": "What is the function of the periosteum?",
//         "option1": "Produce blood cells",
//         "option2": "Store calcium",
//         "option3": "Provide a blood supply to bone",
//         "option4": "Reduce friction",
//         "option5": "House bone marrow",
//         "ans": 3
//     },
//     {
//         "question": "Which bone marking is a small flat area for articulation?",
//         "option1": "Tubercle",
//         "option2": "Fossa",
//         "option3": "Condyle",
//         "option4": "Facet",
//         "option5": "Epicondyle",
//         "ans": 4
//     },
//     {
//         "question": "Which cells in bone are responsible for maintaining bone tissue?",
//         "option1": "Osteoclasts",
//         "option2": "Osteoblasts",
//         "option3": "Chondrocytes",
//         "option4": "Fibroblasts",
//         "option5": "Osteocytes",
//         "ans": 5
//     },
    
//         {
//             "question": "What is the primary process of bone development directly from mesenchyme called?",
//             "option1": "Endochondral ossification",
//             "option2": "Intramembranous ossification",
//             "option3": "Periosteal ossification",
//             "option4": "Metaphyseal ossification",
//             "option5": "Epiphyseal ossification",
//             "ans": 2
//         },
//         {
//             "question": "Which cells are responsible for the formation of the cartilaginous bone model during endochondral ossification?",
//             "option1": "Osteoblasts",
//             "option2": "Chondroblasts",
//             "option3": "Osteocytes",
//             "option4": "Fibroblasts",
//             "option5": "Adipocytes",
//             "ans": 2
//         },
//         {
//             "question": "Where do periosteal capillaries grow into during the formation of the primary ossification center?",
//             "option1": "Epiphysis",
//             "option2": "Diaphysis",
//             "option3": "Metaphysis",
//             "option4": "Calcified cartilage",
//             "option5": "Bone marrow",
//             "ans": 4
//         },
//         {
//             "question": "What is the name of the bone structure that grows as a bone develops and is formed from the primary ossification center?",
//             "option1": "Epiphysis",
//             "option2": "Metaphysis",
//             "option3": "Diaphysis",
//             "option4": "Periosteum",
//             "option5": "Endosteum",
//             "ans": 3
//         },
//         {
//             "question": "At what period do secondary ossification centers typically appear?",
//             "option1": "Embryonic period",
//             "option2": "Fetal period",
//             "option3": "After birth",
//             "option4": "Puberty",
//             "option5": "Adulthood",
//             "ans": 3
//         },
//         {
//             "question": "Which part of the bone is ossified from the secondary ossification center?",
//             "option1": "Epiphysis",
//             "option2": "Diaphysis",
//             "option3": "Metaphysis",
//             "option4": "Periosteum",
//             "option5": "Endosteum",
//             "ans": 1
//         },
//         {
//             "question": "What name is given to the flared part of the diaphysis nearest the epiphysis?",
//             "option1": "Epiphysis",
//             "option2": "Diaphysis",
//             "option3": "Metaphysis",
//             "option4": "Periosteum",
//             "option5": "Endosteum",
//             "ans": 3
//         },
//         {
//             "question": "What structure intervenes between the diaphysis and epiphyses during the growth of a long bone?",
//             "option1": "Periosteum",
//             "option2": "Epiphysial plate",
//             "option3": "Endosteum",
//             "option4": "Haversian system",
//             "option5": "Bone marrow",
//             "ans": 2
//         },
//         {
//             "question": "What term describes the fusion seam formed when the diaphysis and epiphyses fuse?",
//             "option1": "Epiphysial line",
//             "option2": "Periosteum",
//             "option3": "Metaphysis",
//             "option4": "Endosteum",
//             "option5": "Osteon",
//             "ans": 1
//         },
//         {
//             "question": "Which bone is an example of a short bone that develops a secondary ossification center?",
//             "option1": "Calcaneus",
//             "option2": "Humerus",
//             "option3": "Femur",
//             "option4": "Tibia",
//             "option5": "Fibula",
//             "ans": 1
//         },
//         {
//             "question": "What are the small, worm-like bones that are often found along the sutures of the cranium called?",
//             "option1": "Accessory bones",
//             "option2": "Supernumerary bones",
//             "option3": "Sutural bones",
//             "option4": "Heterotopic bones",
//             "option5": "Sesamoid bones",
//             "ans": 3
//         },
//         {
//             "question": "What type of arteries are mainly responsible for nourishing the compact bone?",
//             "option1": "Nutrient arteries",
//             "option2": "Periosteal arteries",
//             "option3": "Metaphyseal arteries",
//             "option4": "Epiphysial arteries",
//             "option5": "Haversian arteries",
//             "ans": 2
//         },
//         {
//             "question": "Which nerves cause constriction or dilation of blood vessels within bones?",
//             "option1": "Sensory nerves",
//             "option2": "Periosteal nerves",
//             "option3": "Vasomotor nerves",
//             "option4": "Autonomic nerves",
//             "option5": "Haversian nerves",
//             "ans": 3
//         },
//     [
//         {
//             "question": "What is the common imaging method used to assess normal and diminished bone mass?",
//             "option1": "MRI",
//             "option2": "CT scan",
//             "option3": "Ultrasound",
//             "option4": "Bone scanning",
//             "option5": "X-ray",
//             "ans": 4
//         },
//         {
//             "question": "Where is bone marrow commonly harvested from due to its accessibility?",
//             "option1": "Femur",
//             "option2": "Humerus",
//             "option3": "Sternum",
//             "option4": "Tibia",
//             "option5": "Radius",
//             "ans": 3
//         },
//         {
//             "question": "Which cells proliferate and secrete collagen during the healing of a bone fracture?",
//             "option1": "Osteoblasts",
//             "option2": "Chondrocytes",
//             "option3": "Fibroblasts",
//             "option4": "Osteocytes",
//             "option5": "Adipocytes",
//             "ans": 3
//         },
//         {
//             "question": "What is the condition characterized by a reduction in the quantity of bone, often seen in the elderly?",
//             "option1": "Osteomyelitis",
//             "option2": "Osteosarcoma",
//             "option3": "Osteopenia",
//             "option4": "Osteoarthritis",
//             "option5": "Osteoporosis",
//             "ans": 5
//         },
//         {
//             "question": "What is the term for the imaging method used to evaluate bone marrow?",
//             "option1": "Bone scanning",
//             "option2": "Bone densitometry",
//             "option3": "Sternal puncture",
//             "option4": "X-ray",
//             "option5": "CT scan",
//             "ans": 3
//         },
    
//         {
//             "question": "What type of fractures are most common in children?",
//             "option1": "Comminuted fractures",
//             "option2": "Greenstick fractures",
//             "option3": "Open fractures",
//             "option4": "Pathological fractures",
//             "option5": "Spiral fractures",
//             "ans": 2
//         },
//         {
//             "question": "What is the first step in the formation of a cartilaginous bone model during endochondral ossification?",
//             "option1": "Differentiation of osteoblasts",
//             "option2": "Condensation of mesenchymal cells",
//             "option3": "Vascular invasion",
//             "option4": "Formation of the periosteal bud",
//             "option5": "Calcification of cartilage",
//             "ans": 2
//         },
//         {
//             "question": "Which cells are involved in bone resorption?",
//             "option1": "Osteoblasts",
//             "option2": "Chondrocytes",
//             "option3": "Osteoclasts",
//             "option4": "Fibroblasts",
//             "option5": "Osteocytes",
//             "ans": 3
//         },
//         {
//             "question": "What term is used for the microscopic canal systems in compact bone?",
//             "option1": "Volkmann's canals",
//             "option2": "Haversian systems",
//             "option3": "Lacunae",
//             "option4": "Canaliculi",
//             "option5": "Trabeculae",
//             "ans": 2
//         },
//         {
//             "question": "What is the role of osteogenic cells associated with the periosteal bud?",
//             "option1": "Bone resorption",
//             "option2": "Bone formation",
//             "option3": "Cartilage formation",
//             "option4": "Blood vessel formation",
//             "option5": "Nerve formation",
//             "ans": 2
//         },
//         {
//             "question": "What do we call the thickened trabeculae or lines of arrested growth in bones?",
//             "option1": "Epiphysial lines",
//             "option2": "Haversian lines",
//             "option3": "Calcification lines",
//             "option4": "Growth lines",
//             "option5": "Dense lines",
//             "ans": 5
//         },
//         {
//             "question": "Which type of bone fracture leaves a sharp, often uneven edge of bone?",
//             "option1": "Epiphysial displacement",
//             "option2": "Greenstick fracture",
//             "option3": "Comminuted fracture",
//             "option4": "Spiral fracture",
//             "option5": "Pathological fracture",
//             "ans": 1
//         },
//         {
//             "question": "What term describes the bone condition resulting from loss of arterial supply?",
//             "option1": "Osteomyelitis",
//             "option2": "Osteoporosis",
//             "option3": "Osteosarcoma",
//             "option4": "Avascular necrosis",
//             "option5": "Osteopenia",
//             "ans": 4
//         },
//         {
//             "question": "Which structures are particularly dense and recognizable in sectioned bone or radiographs after epiphysial fusion?",
//             "option1": "Periosteum",
//             "option2": "Epiphysial lines",
//             "option3": "Osteons",
//             "option4": "Trabeculae",
//             "option5": "Haversian canals",
//             "ans": 2
//         },
//         {
//             "question": "What is the purpose of the nutrient arteries in long bones?",
//             "option1": "Provide blood supply to periosteum",
//             "option2": "Supply blood to the compact bone of the shaft",
//             "option3": "Nourish the epiphyses",
//             "option4": "Supply blood to the joint surfaces",
//             "option5": "Provide blood supply to the periosteal nerves",
//             "ans": 2
//         },
//         {
//             "question": "Which type of bones sometimes form in soft tissues where they are not normally present?",
//             "option1": "Sutural bones",
//             "option2": "Supernumerary bones",
//             "option3": "Heterotopic bones",
//             "option4": "Sesamoid bones",
//             "option5": "Accessory bones",
//             "ans": 3
//         },
//         {
//             "question": "Which imaging technique is often used to predict adult height in adolescents?",
//             "option1": "MRI",
//             "option2": "CT scan",
//             "option3": "Ultrasound",
//             "option4": "Bone age radiographs",
//             "option5": "X-ray",
//             "ans": 4
//         },
//         {
//             "question": "What is the term for the bone collar formed during the healing of a fracture?",
//             "option1": "Periosteal collar",
//             "option2": "Epiphysial collar",
//             "option3": "Callus",
//             "option4": "Haversian collar",
//             "option5": "Metaphyseal collar",
//             "ans": 3
//         }
//     ]
    
    
// ]